Anthony Mwai Maina

Software Engineer & Data Scientist

+254794552713/ +254785018500

Email: mainaanthonymwai@gmail

Github: https://github.com/mainaanthony (primary),

https://github.com/ggt-anthony-maina (professional).

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/anthony mwai-973b45209/

P.O. BOX 1246-00618, Ruiru, Kiambu

Profile

I am a Software Engineer who loves to learn and experiment. My experiences have served me well in developing good problem-solving skills and becoming a team player with an eye for detail to find creative solutions to evolving problems. I am driven to acquire proper hands-on skills in the up-to date programming languages and other considerations. I aim to become a proficient leader informed in software development, CI/CD pipelines, web hosting, security and data analysis

Skills

Languages: Python, Java, C#, JavaScript, SQL, HTML, CSS, SASS

Frontend: JavaScript, React, Next JS, Angular, Graph-QL(Apollo)

Mobile: Java

Testing: Jest using Test-Bed and Spectator, X-Unit, Cypress

DEV-Ops – CI/CD pipelines using Docker, Git-hub Actions

Backend: NodeJS, REST API, Microservices, C# using .Net Core, Hot

Chocolate for Graph -QL, Nest JS

Databases: Relational database (MSSQL, MySQL, ORACLE), Non-

Relational databases (MongoDB, POSTGRESQL), in-memory Databases

(Redis), KAFKA, ERWIN, KUBERNETES

Data Analysis: Python, Advanced Excel

Visualization & Reports: Power Bi, Tableau

Strong analytical & problem-solving skills, Excellent communication skills

Version Control: Git, Git Actions

Experience

Griffin Global Technologies / Software Engineer

Feb 2024- Present

NYERI, KENYA

Developed an advanced internal HR Tool enhancing employee management by efficiently tracking projects, skills, certifications, and employee status. Empowered HR to strategically assign personnel based on expertise and project history, optimizing workforce allocation and productivity.

Developed actively with a team a client HR product tool, meant for implementing streamlined tools for report management and file format optimizations through electronic data interchange (EDI). This ensured that the organization was able to keep their clients employees documents involved in health and benefits, secure when doing transfers by using secure protocols when doing such transfers using defined formats and procedures.

Skills, tools & specializations: FRONT- END: React, Angular, JavaScript, Redux, Apollo Graph-QL

NodeJS, C#(ASP .NET Core), REST API, Microservices, Git, Docker, Azure Functions(Serverless)

Databases: Relational database (MSSQL), in-memory Databases (Redis)

Graph-QL

Testing Frameworks: Jest with spectator, X-Unit

ARTSAM Technologies Limited/ Data Modeler

August 2023 - January 2024

NYERI, KENYA

I was able to translate business requirements into data models to support big data platform solutions and work with the Application development team to Implement data strategies, build data flows and develop conceptual data models.

I was also responsible for best practices in data modelling and responsible for design, building and maintenance of data architectures for complex, highly business intelligence and analytic solutions that are both flexible and scalable.

I was engaged in data transformations and loading of data from various source systems.

Skills, tools & specializations: Oracle, Postgres, Kafka, Kubernetes, Erwin, Git

The Jitu /Full Stack Software Engineer Trainee

April 2023- July 2023 NYERI, KENYA

I was able to undergo this three-months intensive program in Full stack Web development, acquiring knowledge to be able to develop websites professionally and of enterprise standards.

Skills, tools & specializations: FRONT- END: React, JavaScript, Redux NodeJS, REST API, Microservices, Git

Databases: Relational database (MSSQL), in-memory Databases (Redis)

Freelancer / Software Engineer & Data analyst

Jan 2023- PRESENT

NYERI, KENYA

Interacted with various datasets from clients to give insights and also use python scripts to clean and give insights to datasets.

I have together with other individuals, been able to build various web and mobile applications as per client's specifications.

Skills, tools & specializations – MySQL, MongoDB, Python Figma, React, MSSQL, Advanced Excel, Power Bi, Tableau, Git

County Government of Nyandarua / ICT Officer attachee

(Lands and Rates Department)

January 2022 - April 2022

NYANDARUA, KENYA

Managed data from the database of licenses, leases and land rates fees.

Networking and computer hardware & software repair & maintenance.

Analyzed data to provide insights.

Skills, tools & specializations – Java, HTML, CSS, UNIX

Education

Dedan Kimathi University of Technology / Degree

MAY 2019 - APRIL 2023

Bachelor of Science In Computer Science.

Organizations

Google Developer Groups / Nyeri

NOVEMBER 2022 - PRESENT

A community of passionate developers interested in learning about and building with google technologies.

React-Native Community / Nairobi

FEBRUARY 2023- PRESENT

A learning community for software engineers to advance their careers and solve common issues when using react-native.

Career Objectives

To work as a software engineer and data scientist applying my knowledge in the field of development, designing, testing, analysis and maintenance to cater to the specific needs of the people.

I wish to work in a team of motivated individuals who wish to work towards the advancement of the company and its goals.